I'm Jason Hoffman and my goal is to help
you have the confidence to just press go
live in a previous video I told you that
was one thing that would level up my
live stream to make it next level my one
thing all I want for Christmas is this
mobile router and I'd like to take the
time to show you why this one mobile
router is the thing that would level up
my live streaming experience well here
it is it is the Slate ax 1800 personal
Wi-Fi router the reason why this is the
one thing I think will level up my live
stream boils down to two Simple Things
One a five volt three amp power bank
Source will power it and two it's Wi-Fi
six everything else that it will do and
there's a lot all of that's just icing
those two things mean I can power this
with my elect jet 10 000 milliamp hour
battery Bank
and Wi-Fi six means it's going to handle
all of my connections everything that
produces local traffic in my mobile live
stream will be handled by this little
device there are several versions of
this same little mobile router with
different specifications of course this
particular one is the one I think will
level up my live stream because of the
tech specs it holds on the 2.4 gigahertz
range it's going to give me 600 megabits
per second transfer speed
on the five gigahertz side of it it's
going to give me 1.2 gigabit transfer
speed
it says it'll do 120 devices at a time I
have not tested that piece and it's
multiple user memo multiple user
multiple in multiple out so every user
that's connected to it every device
that's connected to it gets a multiple
in multiple app there's no waiting in
line for data to finish transferring
before other data can go which means all
the local traffic ceases to be the
bottleneck for my live stream by the way
it's also built software wise on the
open wrt platform so custom software is
a possibility even though I don't
operate in those circles it does have a
cooling fan built in which kicks on when
the CPU gets to above 75 degrees Celsius
now getting internet into it there's
three different ways we can get internet
into this device and then how it handles
that internet can be done in a various
we've got a storm blowing through today
and the rain is hitting the window next
to me there are three different ways to
get data into this device for streaming
and once it's in the device there are
several different ways the device will
handle it can be a repeater it can be
its own Standalone router it can be an
access point so you have a lot of
options when you go into its web page
control panel now getting internet into
it is as simple as turning it on and
letting it find a local Wi-Fi signal it
will then repeat that signal it can be
used as an extension of that same signal
you can use it as a Wi-Fi repeater if
you want to you can also plug an
ethernet cable into the WAN Port the WAN
Port which is going to bring in wide
area network data so you can you can
have data access internet access at your
mobile live stream now plugging that in
from another router that already already
exists in the Press Box or bringing your
own router with you your mobile router
your cellular router for me it's an
incigo MiFi hotspot I'm going to adapt
out of that in sigo via USB to ethernet
adapter and then I'm going to go from
ethernet to ethernet on the light area
Network Port of this router and then I'm
going to have a network that I can use
either Wi-Fi or wired there are two
local area network reports two ethernet
Jacks that I can use to wire in all my
devices in order to have a stable live
stream
and the third way we can get internet
into this device is by the USB port I
can actually turn on the hotspot on my
cell phone plug into the cell phone and
to the
slate router and it's going to use that
piece of internet in order to have data
for my live stream so three different
ways depending on what kind of
connection I have available to me when I
get to the spot where I'm doing my
mobile live stream my go-to here is
going to be using the MiFi hotspot to
the ethernet port I'll turn the Wi-Fi
off on the hotspot and let it focus on
just talking to the cell tower then the
Slate will be the connection point for
everything about my live streaming setup
the electjet 10 000 milliamp hour
battery that I love will power this
device
for about 30 percent a little less than
30 percent per hour so I'll get a little
over three hours of streaming
active streaming
if I use my battery power to power this
little device of course if I'm in a
place where I can plug it in plug it in
is great but there are many times that
I'm needing to set up beside a baseball
fence there's no power to be found and I
need to have a couple of power banks
that will power all of my mobile live
stream it actually works really very
well for the testing that I did today I
did in fact use my YOLO box Pro
I used a rockware PTZ 10x camera
that does also receive power via USB so
I had a second 10 000 milliamp hour
battery that I use to power that little
PTZ camera
I plugged it into the USB port on the
yellow box Pro and then I just set up my
stream to be wired in my ncgo MiFi
hotspot directly connected to the Slate
router and from the router directly
connected to the yolobox pro via
Ethernet cable and then I set it up to
stream and went out and got some lunch
about an hour and a half later I came
back and it had used just over 30
percent of the battery on the the
electricity to use very little battery
for the PTZ camera and of course I was
using the internal battery for the YOLO
box Pro but in that in that test I had
zero dropped frames I can I had a
consistent 3
000 kilobits per second upload according
to the data that I see on my yolobox Pro
now I do Bond my connections with yellow
box Pro I did side load speedify on my
YOLO box and so I'm able to use its
Cellular Connection I have a SIM card in
it and I'm able to use the setup that I
have here with the Slate router as two
separate internet connections that are
both bonded into one and so I don't
struggle for any kind of upload speed
I'm very confident in it so long as I
have good service from my local local
service provider where in the location
where I'm streaming from my next test of
this router will involve taking it to
the baseball field and to the football
field and testing the distances that I
can I can get out of this from the
camera back to my setup wherever it is
Press Box or beside the fence so that I
can test how far I can space these
cameras out and still use a Wi-Fi
connection for a couple of my cameras
while I'm using an ethernet connection
for the ones that I can plug into to the
yellow box Pro or into the router itself
if you have experience using a personal
Wi-Fi router let us know which one
you've used and what your experience was
with it